Guide to the Nichols Family Correspondence
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1769-1873; Series I; 6.67; (19 boxes)
  - Brydges, Sir Samuel Egerton, Bart., 1762-1832. 23 ALS to John Nichols, [v.p.], 1792 Jun 25-1818 Jan 8 (Box 3)
    Letters between editor and contributor to the Gentleman's Magazine. Topics include Brydge's claim to the Chandos Barony, reviews, and antiquarian pursuits. Among the letters are two to the editor of the GM about the Chandos claim, signed "Sudeley."
  - Buchan, David Steuart Erksine, 11th Earl of, 1742-1829. ALS to John Nichols, Edinburgh, 1785 Oct 6 (Box 3)
  - Buckler, John, 1770-1851
    - ALS to Nichols & Co., New Kent Rd., 1837 Dec 23 (Box 3)
    - ALS to John Gough Nichols, [n.p.], 1844 Jul 10 (Box 3)
  - Buckler, John Chessel, 1793-1894
    - 31 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [v.p.], 1811 Oct 15-1830 Sep 27 (Box 3)
      Letters from author to publisher about engravings, proofs, subscriptions, friends, and the Gentleman's Magazine.
    - ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [n.p.], 1833 Nov 9 (Box 3)
      Thanks him for finding room for a neglected church in the Gentleman's Magazine; also writes that Lord Brownlow has subscribed.
    - ALS to John Gough Nichols, New Kent Road, 1835 May 27 (Box 3)
      Sends another of the curious old houses in Somersetshire for the Magazine and begs in return a copy of the Magdalene book.
  - Bulmer, William, 1757-1830. ALS and LS to John Bowyer Nichols, Clapham Rise, 1825 Sep 12 (Box 3)
    Asks him to insert advertisement in the Gentleman's Magazine. Also solicits his "proxy in behalf of Miriam Atkin, a candidate for admission in the London Orphan Asylum at the Election in January."
  - Bunce, Wheler, 1757-1809. 2 ALS to John Nichols, Mar, Sandwich, 1787 Jan 19 (Box 4)
    Concerns the Gentleman's Magazine and other literary subjects.
  - Bunce, William. 8 ALS to John Nichols, Westerham, 1803 Jan 21-1811 Nov 19 (Box 4)
    On literary subjects and corrections in the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Burder, J. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [n.p.], 1826 (Box 4)
    Personal business.
  - Burgess, Thomas, Bp. of Salisbury, 1756-1837. 21 ALS to John Nichols, [v.p.], 1784 Feb 1-1815 Jan 2 (Box 4)
    About books, suggested publications, printing instructions and antiquarian questions. Letters contain references to Charles Burney.
  - Burke, Sir John Bernard, 1814-1892. 2 ALS to John Gough Nichols, Dublin Castle, 1870 Dec 22 (Box 4)
    On the book trade, the Gentleman's Magazine, and personal health.
  - Burnaby, Andrew, 1732-1812
    - ALS to Joseph Cradock, Baggrave Hall, 1797 Apr 21 (Box 4)
    - ALS to John Nichols, Greenwich, 1799 Apr 2 (Box 4)
      Provides autobiographical data for Nichol's Literary Anecdotes and evaluates proof for upcoming work.
  - Burnaby, Thomas Beaumont, 1742-1823. ALS to John Nichols, Asfordby, 1798 Aug 2 (Box 4)
    Genealogical information for Nichol's History of Leicestershire.
  - Burney, Charles, 1757-1817. 5 ALS and 1 AL (3d person) to John Nichols, [v.p.], 1787 Aug 12-1809 Oct 31 (Box 4)
    Concerns works Burney wants to have published and books he wants to buy.
  - Burney, Charles Parr, 1785-1864
    - 17 ALS to John Nichols, [v.p.], 1809 Oct 19-1825 Feb 9 (Box 4)
      About literary matters, friends, and the printing business. Mentions Samuel Parr.
    - 6 ALS and 1 AL (3d person) to John Bowyer Nichols, [v.p.], 1819 Sep 22-1858 Jul 7 (Box 4)
      Personal letters concerning the Gentleman's Magazine, book trade and club affairs.
  - Burrell, Sir Charles. AL to Nichols & Co., Grosvenor Place, [n.y.] Apr 7 (Box 4)
    Declines to buy book.
  - Burrell, George. 2 ALS to John Nichols, [v.p.], 1814 Oct 4-1816 Aug 8 (Box 4)
    One letter extends thanks from the Brethren of the Society of United Friars and the other asks Nichols for any extra autographs he might have for a collection.
  - Burton, F. ALS to John Nichols, 1813 Mar 28 (Box 4)
    Asks for genealogical information.
  - Butler, Charles, 1750-1832. 7 ALS to John Nichols, Lincoln's Inn, 1798 May 7-1819 Oct 25 (Box 4)
    About the Gentleman's Magazine and book orders.
  - Butler, George, 1774-1853. 3 AL (3d person) to John Nichols, Shrewsbury, 1820 Jan 7-Feb 22 (Box 4)
    Accepts dinner invitations and inquires about the Gentleman's Magazine. Accompanied by two letters to Nichols & Co.
  - Butler, R. AL (3d person) to John Bowyer Nichols, 1840 Jun 10 (Box 4)
    Sends publication.
  - Butler, Samuel, Bp. of Lichfield, 1774-1839
    - ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Shrewsbury, 1813 May 9 (Box 4)
      Corrections to a previous letter to the editor of the Gentleman's Magazine.
    - AL (3d person) to John Bowyer Nichols, Suffolk St., 1837 May 13 (Box 4)
      Thanks for sending publication.
  - Butler, Walter. 5 ALS and 1 AL to John Nichols, Havant, 1797 Mar 5-1812 May 13 (Box 4)
    Book orders and antiquarian comments.
  - Butler, Weeden, 1742-1823. 10 ALS to John Nichols, Chelsea, 1797 Dec 1-1819 Apr 19 (Box 4)
    About the Gentleman's Magazine, proof corrections, book orders, and other literary subjects.
  - Butler, Weeden, 1773-1831
    - ALS to [John Nichols], Chelsea, 1820 Jun 9 (Box 4)
      Cover letter for review of Thomas Faulkner's Kensington, asking for proofs, and for the May issue of Gentleman's Magazine.
    - 9 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Chelsea, 1810 Sep 11-1826 Jan 4 (Box 4)
      Concerns the Gentleman's Magazine: letters to the editor, obituaries and fictional pieces.
  - Butt, John, ca. 1756-1831. 7 ALS to John Nichols, [v.p.], 1791 Jan 7-1815 Mar 27 (Box 4)
    Answers to queries about antiquarian subjects such as the pedigree of the Earl of Harborough and information for Nichols's History of Leicestershire.
  - Bye, D., 1744-. 7 ALS to John Nichols, Peckham, 1789 May 21-1821 Oct 24 (Box 4)
    Letters about the book trade and the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Byerley, Sir John. AL (3d person) to John Nichols, Leu Taverny, near Paris, 1816 Sep 9 (Box 4)
    Sends article for the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Byerley, Thomas, d. 1826. ALS to John Nichols, Finsbury Square, 1814 Aug 30 (Box 4)
    Reports on historical research he did in the British Museum.
  - Calder, John, 1733-1815. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [n.p.], 1814 Oct 25 (Box 5)
    Thanks him for information about Allison's works and asks him to procure his sermons.
  - Cambridge, George Owen, 1756-1841. ALS and AL (3d person) to John Bowyer Nichols, Trickenham Meadow, 1808 Nov 10-1832 Jan 7 (Box 5)
    On church matters.
  - Carey, John, 1756-1826. ALS to [John Bowyer Nichols?], Islington, [1804 or later] Jul 15 (Box 5)
    Requests that an article of his be included in the next Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Carlos, Edward John, 1798-1851. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Walwark, 1845 Jul 15 (Box 5)
    On topographical and antiquarian subjects.
  - Carney, H. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Greenwich, [n.y.] May 20 (Box 5)
    Instructions to publisher.
  - Carter, N. G. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Temple, 1837 Jan 18 (Box 5)
    Asks that an article of his be considered for publication in the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Cartwright, Edmund, 1774-1833
    - ALS to John Gough Nichols, Arundel, 1829 Nov 6 (Box 5)
      About a problem of fitting a pedigree into Cartwright's Topography of Sussex.
    - ALS to the Duke of Norfolk, Arundel, 1831 Jun 24 (Box 5)
      Asks the Duke to send "two plates of Arundel Castle" to Nichols & Son so that they can be included in "my reprint of Mr. Dallaways second volume."
    - ALS to John Gough Nichols, Arundel, 1829 Aug 13-1831 Aug 8 (Box 5)
      Concerns proofs for his book and other printing matters.
  - Cassan, Stephen Hyde, 1789-1841. 2 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [v.p.], 1828 Feb 22-1835 Mar 11 (Box 5)
    About his work and a recommendation of a new employee for Nichols & Co.
  - Cecil, J. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, St. Helen's Place, 1860[?] Jul 7 (Box 5)
    Asks for material to use in a History of Hertfordshire.
  - Chetwynd, Sir George, Bart., 1783-1850. ALS to Nichols & Co., Grendan Hall, 1833 Nov 27 (Box 5)
    Concerns proofs.
  - Child, Sir Josiah, 1630-1699. Notes on the life and work of Sir Josiah Child (Box 5)
    Anonymous manuscript in several hands.
  - Churton, Ralph, 1754-1831
    - 4 ALS to John Nichols, Middleton, 1812 Mar 23-1814 Dec 22 (Box 5)
      Congratulates Nichols on completion of his "Magnum Opus" ( The Literary Anecdotes ). In a later letter he sends corrections for the last volume. Also comments on church politics.
    - ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Middleton, 1823 Mar 14 (Box 5)
      Requests that his article on tithes be included in the next Gentleman's Magazine. Congratulates Bowyer on his father's birthday.
  - Clarke, Anne. ALS to John Nichols, [n.p.], 1819 Oct 27 (Box 5)
    Thanks Nichols for a gift and sends epigram.
  - Clarkson, E. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Stockwell, 1831 Aug 10 (Box 5)
    About payment for an article in the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Cork, Edmund Boyle, 8th earl of, 1767-1856. ALS to Mr. Nichols, Marston, 1836 Jan 11 (Box 5)
  - Cork, Mary (Monckton) Boyle, Countess of, 1748-1840. ALS to John Nichols, Dublin Castle, [n.y.] Apr 11 (Box 5)
    Offers her assistance for Nichol's History and Antiquities of Leicester.
  - Courthope, William, 1808-1866. ALS to John Gough Nichols, College of Arms, 1860 May 5 (Box 5)
    Recommends a candidate for Nichols's vote in the National Benefit election.
  - Cowe, James. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Sunbury Vicarage, 1806 Jan 21 (Box 5)
    Asks Nichols to print 500 copies of his new book.
  - Cradock, Joseph, 1742-1826. 4 letters (copies) to John Nichols, [n.p.], 1826 Feb 14-Nov (Box 5)
    Correspondence between two old friends in the last years of their lives.
  - Crew, J. J. 2 LS to John Bowyer Nichols, Staple Inn, Holborn, 1860 Mar 1, 2 (Box 5)
    About legal affairs.
  - Croker, Thomas Crofton, 1798-1854. 5 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Admiralty, 1840 Feb 4-1849 Mar 24 (Box 5)
    Concerns the activities of the Royal Literary Fund and his work.
  - D., T. ALS to Mr. Milliken, Bath, 1791 Oct 10 (Box 5)
    Allows Milliken to use him as a reference for credit purposes with John Nichols.
  - Dartmouth, William Legge, 4th earl of, 1784-1853. ALS to [Nichols & Co.], Berkeley House, [1817] Apr 17 (Box 5)
  - Davids, C. J. ALS to Nichols & Co., Piccadilly, 1841 Feb 15 (Box 5)
    Directs booksellers to send a publication to his home before ten.
  - Davies, Robert, 1793-1875. ALS to John Gough Nichols, The Mount, York, 1873 Jan 15 (Box 5)
    Concerns the pedigree of the Hungate family. Accompanied by a newspaper article of 1838 reporting on a trial to recover the Hungate estate and Nichols's notes on the family's ancestry.
  - Davis, Mark. ALS to Nichols & Co., Turnwood, 1830 Mar 14 (Box 5)
  - Davy, Henry, fl. 1829
    - ALS to Nichols & Co., Chequer Sq., 1819 Dec 5 (Box 5)
    - ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Ipswich, 1846 Dec 19 (Box 5)
      About prints he made for Nichols.
  - Domville, Maria. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Highgate, [1810 or later] Oct 4 (Box 6)
    Thanks for services rendered and recommendations for new employees.
  - Dorchester, Guy Carleton, 3d Baron, 1811-1875. AL (3d person) to Nichols & Co., Dorchester, 1842 Jan 11 (Box 6)
    Requests remaining volumes of work.
  - Dundas, N. P., Mrs. AL (3d person) to Anne Nichols, Bowland, 1853 Dec 20 (Box 6)
    Regrets her inability to promote a Miss Hooper's interest at the May election.
  - Dunster, Charles, 1750-1816. ALS to [John Nichols], Petworth, n.d. (Box 6)
    On the revising of proofs.
  - Eades, John, 1764-1835. ALS to Nichols and Company, Abbots Norton, 1815 Mar 16 (Box 6)
    Asks to purchase some books and portraits.
  - Edmonds, Richard, 1801-1866. ALS to [John Bowyer Nichols], Redruth, 1835 Jul 22 (Box 6)
    About the use of the term "wish'd" in Cornwall.
  - Ellis, Sir Henry, 1777-1869
    - ALS to J. B. Nichols, British Museum, 1831 Mar 10 (Box 6)
    - 4 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, British Museum, 1823 Apr 7-[1835 or later] (Box 6)
      Concerns various papers for Archaeologia, especially matters of editing and proof-reading.
    - 5 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, British Museum, 1831 Jan 26-1843 Jan 17 (Box 6)
      Correspondence between friends about books and antiquarian matters.
    - ALS to John Gough Nichols, 1829 Mar 9 (Box 6)
    - ALS to John Gough Nichols, [n.p.], n.d. (Box 6)
    - AL (3d person) to Miss Nichols, Beal Square, 1857 Jun 4 (Box 6)
  - Ellis, J. J. ALS to [John Bowyer Nichols], College Hill, 1805 Sep 11 (Box 6)
    Contains a Statute from a Merchant Taylor's School dated 1625 regarding re-entry.
  - Evans, Edward, 1818-1860. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Strand, 1860 Jul 17 (Box 6)
    Asks if Nichols would be willing to sell him an engraving of Bartholomew Fair by Hogarth.
  - Fallofield, William. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Waner St., 1831 Mar 12 (Box 6)
    Book orders.
  - Falmouth, Edward Boscawen, 2d Earl of, 1787-1841. 2 AL (3d person) to John Bowyer Nichols, Newberry, 1836 May 30-1837 Aug 16 (Box 6)
    About proofs for book.
  - Fanshawe, J. G. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Board of Trade, 1861 Aug 21 (Box 6)
    Relays Sir James Tennent's request for a copy of a petition not included in the Parliamentary Papers.
  - Farrer, James. AL (3d person) to Miss Anne Nichols, St. John's College, [ca. 1824] May 7 (Box 6)
    Mr. Farrer ... grieves excessively that an absurd regulation, to the intent that every man must be in College every night by 12, renders it impossible for him to accept her kind invitation.
  - Farthing, John. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Parliament St., 1860 Sep 8-12 (Box 6)
    Employee informs his vacationing boss about the business during his absence.
  - Ferguson, James Frederic, 1807-1855. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Exchequer Record Office, 1855 Jun 21 (Box 6)
    Wants to publish an article on the "purely Celtic custom" relating to "Short Ploughs."
  - Ferrers, Robert Shirley, 7th Earl, 1756-1827. ALS to John Nichols, Covent, 1804 Sep 27 (Box 6)
    Asks that his daughter's marriage be mentioned in the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Figgins, S. ALS to Mr. Nuttall, West St., 1855 Oct 26 (Box 6)
  - Firth, James. ALS to John Nichols, Town Clerk's Office, 1819 Oct 9 (Box 6)
    Asks Nichols to "prepare the necessary accounts" and come to his office.
  - Fisher, George. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Swaffham, Norfolk, 1832 Mar 14 (Box 6)
  - Fisher, S. 46 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [v.p.], 1836 Jun 30-1839 Apr 10 (Box 7)
    About topographical and antiquarian subjects. Continues her brother Thomas's connection with Nichols & Co.
  - Fisher, Thomas, 1781?-1836
    - 155 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Gloucester Terrace, 1830 Oct 1-1836 Jun 21; 6 (Box 7)
      Long correspondence about antiquarian, printing and topographical matters. Includes advertisements and notes for his History of Bedfordshire.
    - AL (draft) to the Duke of Bedford, [n.p.], 1817 (Box 7)
      Sends the third and fourth volumes of his History of Bedfordshire.
  - Ford, James, 1779-1850. 20 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, [v.p.], 1824 Apr 19-1841 Aug 12 (Box 7)
  - Ford, Latitia (Jermyn), d. 1848. 6 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Navestock Vicarage, 1831 Jan 28-1838 Apr 27 (Box 7)
    Concerns her husband James Ford's article for the Gentleman's Magazine and the Literary Illustrations of the 18th Century.
  - Forrester, Joseph James, 1809-1861. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Mark Lane, 1854 Mar 7 (Box 7)
    Financial dealings.
  - Fosbroke, Thomas Dudley, 1770-1842
    - 2 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Walford, 1819 Jun 26, 1828 Jul 4 (Box 7)
      First letter sends printing instructions for the History of the City of Gloucester and asks for business advice. Fosbroke bemoans the fact that an Encyclopedia "for the Science of Antiquities" had never been printed thus foreshadowing publication of his Encyclopedia of Antiquities in 1825.
    - ALS to [Nichols & Co.], 1810 Nov 2 (Box 7)
      Requests the delivery of seven copies of his Gloucester to the order of Wr. Bate.
  - Foss, Edward, 1787-1870. 2 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Essex St., 1829 Dec 12, 1830 Jul 17 (Box 7)
    Personal correspondence.
  - Foss, Henry. 2 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Devonshire St., 1859 Jul 6-1862 Feb 3 (Box 7)
    Correspondence between friends concerning club news, health and books.
  - Francis, George Grant, 1814-1882. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Swansea, 1840 Sep 1 (Box 7)
    Asks Nichols to print his letter in the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - Francis, Thomas. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Dalston Rise, 1860 Apr 10 (Box 7)
    Asks for support at the next Court of the Stationer's Company.
  - Fraser, James, d. 1841. ALS to Nichols & Co., Regent St., 1834 Jan 27 (Box 7)
    Wants to exchange subscription.
  - Freeling, Sir Francis, Bart., 1764-1836. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, General Post Office, 1827 Jul 20 (Box 7)
  - French, Josiah. ALS to unnamed recipient, Windsor, 1849 Sep 4 (Box 7)
    About collections of letters.
  - Frost, Charles, 1781?-1862
    - 12 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Hull, 1827 Mar 13-1843 Feb 4 (Box 7)
      Instructions to his printer concerning subscriptions, changes in an article and acquisitions for "our Library." Includes reply by Nichols.
    - 5 ALS to John Gough Nichols, Hull, 1827 Apr 16-1858 Nov 5 (Box 7)
      About genealogies, the Hull Literary and Philosophical Society and the Gentleman's Magazine.
    - ALS to Nichols & Co., Hull, 1824 Oct 13 (Box 7)
      Asks to be inserted on subscription list for Fosbroke's Encyclopedia of Antiquities.
  - Frost, John, 1803-1840. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Blackfriars, 1825 Nov 25 (Box 7)
    Letter to his printer.
  - Gage, Henry Hall Gage, 4th Viscount, 1791-1877. AL (3d person) to Nichols & Co., Frile, 1832 Jan 3 (Box 7)
    Contends he never ordered subscription.
  - Galway, Catherine Elizabeth (Handefield) Monckton-Arundell, Viscountess, 1783-1862. AL (3d person) to Nichols & Co., Highfield, 1839 Jul 18 (Box 7)
    Sends memoirs of cousin, Edward Handefield.
  - Galway, George Edward Monckton- Arundell, 6th viscount, 1805-1876. ALS to Nichols & Co., Serlby, 1837 Mar 27 (Box 7)
  - Galway, William George Monckton- Arundell, 9th Viscount, 1782-1834. AL (3d person) to John Bowyer Nichols, Serlby, 1828 Feb 14 (Box 7)
    Request for books.
  - Gardiner, Thomas. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Highbury Crescent, 1848 May 22 (Box 7)
    Arrangements for meeting.
  - Garrow, Sir William, 1760-1840. AL (3d person) to Nichols & Co., Guildhall, [1844 or later] (Box 7)
    Requests a book.
  - Gilbert, Davies, 1767-1839. ALS to John Nichols, East, 1822 Dec 29 (Box 7)
    On business.
  - Gill, Charles. ALS to [John Bowyer Nichols], [n.p.], n.d. (Box 7)
    Plea for one guinea.
  - Gill, Thomas Hornblower. ALS to "Mr. Urban" [John Gough Nichols], London, 1846 Feb 8 (Box 7)
    Letter to the editor of the Gentleman's Magazine establishing analogies between St. Paul and Aristotle.
  - Glover, J. H. Letter (copy) to John Bowyer Nichols, [n.p.], 1840 Oct 2 (Box 7)
    Personal letter.
  - Goodenough, Samuel, Bp. of Carlisle, 1743-1827. ALS to John Nichols, Ealey, 1796 Oct 10 (Box 7)
  - Gordon, A. 3 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Little Cloisters, 1828 Dec 29-1830 Jun 29 (Box 7)
    Concerns the business and meetings of their parish.
  - Gough, Richard, 1735-1809. 2 ALS to [John Nichols?], Enfield, 1776 May 26-Oct 4 (Box 7)
    Concerns Roger Gale's papers.
  - Graham, George Farquhar, 1789-1867. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Maidenhead, 1838 Oct 29 (Box 7)
    Instructions on where to send copies of his article.
  - Great Britain, Parliament, 1854, House of Commons. Document, signed by Viscount Eversley, House of Commons, 1854 Dec 12 (Box 7)
    Appointing of Nichols & Co. to print the votes and proceedings of the House.
  - Green, Ann. ALS to Isabella Nichols, [n.p.], 1831 Oct 6 (Box 7)
  - Green, C. ALS to Isabella Nichols, [n.p.], n.d. (Box 7)
    Asks for information.
  - Greenhill, Joseph. ALS to [John Gough Nichols], Stationers Hall, 1855 Mar 1 (Box 7)
  - Gregson, Isabella. ALS to [John Bowyer Nichols, Liverpool, 1827 Aug 31 (Box 7)
  - Gregson, Matthew, 1749-1824. 17 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Liverpool, 1823 Apr 1-1824 Jun 24 (Box 7)
    Letters concern printing instructions and subscriptions for his publications and antiquarian matters. Two letters are addressed to John Bowyer and John Gough Nichols jointly. Accompanied by another addressed to John Gough Nichols.
  - Griffith, William Pettit, 1815-1884. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Russell Sq., 1864 May 28 (Box 7)
    Asks Nichols to be present at meeting of the Society of Antiquaries.
  - Gutch, Robert. ALS to John Nichols, Epsom, 1802 Jan 28 (Box 7)
    Asks Nichols to insert notice of the publication of a dictionary by Jonathan Boucher into the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - H., I. E. ALS to John Nichols, [n.p.], 1801 Feb 7 (Box 8)
    Sends a signature specimen for publication in the Gentleman's Magazine.
  - H., J. ALS to [John Bowyer Nichols], Temple, 1834 Dec 25 (Box 8)
    Letter to the editor of the Gentleman's Magazine on the Greek origin of a Latin poem in Coke's First Institute.
  - Hackett, Maria, 1783-1874
    - 36 ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Crosby Square, 1820 Nov 20-1846 Mar 23 (Box 8)
      Letters between writer and publisher concerning proofs, corrections and engravings for her book on St. Paul's Cathedral.
    - 3 ALS to John Gough Nichols, Crosby Square, 1829 Apr 8-1834 Jun 24 (Box 8)
      On proofs and royalties for her book on St. Paul's Cathedral.
    - ALS and AL (3d person) to Nichols & Co., Crosby Square, 1822 Jun 20, 1823 May 8 (Box 8)
      Instructions for the printing of her book.
  - Hailstone, Edward, 1818-1890. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Walton Hall, Wakefield, [n.y.] Aug 26 (Box 8)
    Thanks Nichols for sending a book.
  - Hale, Richard, 1746-1803. 3 ALS to John Nichols, [n.p.], n.d. (Box 8)
    Concerns literary subjects and scholarly controversies.
  - Hallett, Charles William. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Abington St., [1827] (Box 8)
    Asks Nichols to help his friend, Jerome Knapp, become a member of the Athenaem Club.
  - Halliwell-Phillipps, James Orchard, 1820-1889. ALS to John Gough Nichols, South Kensington, 1869 Jun 16 (Box 8)
    Asks for title of a paper by the recently deceased antiquary and Shakespeare scholar, Clarence Hopper, as Halliwell was preparing "a list of poor Hopper's detached pieces in the hope of obtaining a grant for his widow."
  - Hamper, William, 1776-1831. AL to Mr. Nichols, Birmingham, 1821 Nov 17 (Box 8)
    Requests Nichols to use influence to help aged blind lady collect certain annuities.
  - Hancock, John. ALS to John Gough Nichols, London, 1837 Apr 4 (Box 8)
    Letter to the editor of the Gentleman's Magazine about science and naturalists.
  - Hannett, John, 1803-1893. ALS to [John Bowyer Nichols], Lazette, 1837 Aug 12 (Box 8)
    Objects to an unfavorable review of his book, An Inquiry into the Nature and Form of the Books of the Ancients, in the last Gentleman's Magazine. Signs the letter with the pseudonym John Andrews Arnett.
  - Hansard, Luke, 1752-1828. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Printing Office, 1826 May 18 (Box 8)
    Answer to request for a certain selection of articles.
  - Hanshall, J. H. ALS to Mr. Harris, Reading, 1827 Mar 3 (Box 8)
    Asks that Harris return woodcuts lent to John Bowyer Nichols in 1820 and that the new edition of his History of Chester be published in the Gentleman's Magazine. With Nichols's draft reply.
  - Hardy, Francis, 1751-1812. ALS to [Nichols & Co.], Cookston, 1808 Dec 18 (Box 8)
    About the publication of his Memoirs of Charlemont.
  - Hardy, John Stockdale, 1793-1849. ALS to John Bowyer Nichols, Leicester, 1820 May 9 (Box 8)
    Enclosed a friend's review of Britannicus and an account of a local town meeting.
  - Hardy, Sir Thomas Duffus, 1804-1878. ALS to John Gough Nichols, Record Office Tower, 1854 Feb 24 (Box 8)